Guide to the Walter Boychuk Photographs 1912-1961
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
Walter Boychuk photographs
1912-1961
1920-1945
Oregon Historical Society, Davies Family Research Library 1200 SW Park Avenue Portland, Oregon 97205 Phone: 503-306-5240 Fax: 503-219-2040 E-mail: libreference@ohs.org
Org. Lot 977
Boychuk, Walter, 1886-1967
12 cubic feet 1,569 photographic prints in 12 boxes, 2 oversize boxes and 1 oversize folder; 738 photographic prints in 1 album; and 1,500 glass plate and film negatives in 9 boxes
Photographs taken by Walter Boychuk of Portland, Or., including both commercial and private work. Includes portraits and landscapes primarily from Oregon and Washington state, as well as photographs from two commercial projects: the Historic American Building Survey and the Golden Gate International Exposition in San Francisco in 1939.
Biographical Note
Walter Boychuk (1886-1967) worked as a photographer in Oregon for half a century, making portraits of everyone from ordinary citizens to nationally known figures, including Sen. Wayne Morse, J. Robert Oppenheimer, Eleanor Roosevelt, Lowell Thomas, and Norman Thomas.
Boychuk was born Oct. 25, 1886, at Galatia, Austria. He immigrated to Canada in 1903 and came to Portland in 1906, where he began working as a photographer around 1912. For a few years during the late 1920s, he was associated with photographer Frank I. Jones in Boychuk-Jones Studio. They did commercial photography for the Portland Commission on Public Docks, Port of Portland, and other clients. Beginning about 1930, Boychuk operated Boychuk Studio at various locations in Portland until 1949. At that time he estimated he had served 8,000 customers. He continued to work out of his farm home near Tigard in semi-retirement.
In addition to his portrait and commercial work, Boychuk also gained recognition for his architectural and scenic photography. He photographed the buildings designed by a number of prominent architects. In 1930, he was selected by a committee of the Oregon chapter of the American Institute of Architects to create a portfolio of Oregon landmarks for submission to the Pictorial Archives of Early American Architecture. This was a project of the Library of Congress, funded by the Carnegie Foundation. Boychuk also served as photographer for the subsequent Historic American Buildings Survey in the mid-1930s.
Based on his architectural work, Boychuk was named official photographer for the 1939 Golden Gate International Exposition at San Francisco. There he spent two months photographing fair buildings, inside and out and under different lighting conditions, in both black-and-white and color. He also was an avid mountaineer, skier, and member of the Mazamas mountaineering organization.
Although relatively little known compared with other Oregon photographers such as Ray Atkeson and Benjamin Gifford, Boychuk brought his artist’s eye and meticulous printing skills to a body of work that is among the best produced in the state.
Boychuk donated his photographic collection to the Oregon Historical Society about six months before his death in 1967. The collection represents the images he had retained until that time, and it provides a good sample of the kinds of photographic work he did during the course of his career. The images date from circa 1915 through the 1960s, but the bulk of the collection is from the 1920s through the 1940s.
Group 1 of this collection contains biographical material on Walter Boychuk and his wife, Anna, that was collected while this collection was being processed. Group 2 consists of the copy prints made from Boychuk’s original negatives; this representative sampling of his work was printed courtesy of a conservation grant from the Meyer Memorial Trust and contains photographs taken by Boychuk of various locations in Oregon and other states, portraits, ships and transportation, and other subjects, as well as his work for the Historic American Buildings Survey in 1930-1951 and the Golden Gate International Exposition in San Francisco in 1940. Group 3 is a collection of signed, mounted prints of architectural images, which Boychuk made for the Pictorial Archives of Early American Architecture at the Library of Congress in 1930, and includes some produced for the Historic American Buildings Survey as well; these are annotated with his negative numbers. Group 4 consists of a printed booklet of photomechanical reproductions of Boychuk's photographs, entitled "Pictorial Oregon." Group 5 consists of an oversized album, titled “Pacific Northwest by Boychuk,” which provides a retrospective of images Boychuk made throughout his career, most identified in his handwriting and annotated with his negative numbers.
The collection is arranged in the following groups and series:
Group 1: Walter and Anna Boychuk biographical materials, 1930-1940
Group 2: Prints from original negatives, 1918-1961
Series A: Oregon locations (except Portland), 1918-1957
Subseries 1: Cities and towns
Subseries 2: Bonneville Dam
Subseries 3: Columbia River Gorge
Subseries 4: Coast scenery and lighthouses
Subseries 5: Mount Hood
Subseries 6: Eastern Oregon
Subseries 7: Lakes
Subseries 8: Mountains
Subseries 9: Rivers
Subseries 10: Waterfalls
Series B: Portland, Ore., 1925-1951
Series C: Other locations, 1919-1950
Series D: Portraits, 1930-1961
Subseries 1: Men
Subseries 2: Women
Subseries 3: Groups
Series E: Ships and transportation, 1912-1940
Series F: Other subjects, 1918-1940
Series G: Copy work, 1915-1959
Series H: Historic American Buildings Survey, 1930-1951
Subseries 1: Residences
Subseries 2: Buildings
Series I: San Francisco, Golden Gate International Exposition, 1940
Group 3: Vintage prints made by Walter Boychuk, 1922-1957
Series A: Locations, 1930-1957
Series B: Portraits, 1922-1957
Series C: Historic American Buildings Survey, 1930-1951
Group 4: Pictorial Oregon: Twenty-Four Memorable Photographs by Walter Boychuk, 1941
Group 5: "Pacific Northwest by Boychuck" photograph album, undated
The collection is open to the public.
Photo Accession no. 2001D028
A book from Walter Boychuk's personal library, Sunlight and Shadow: A Book for Photographers, Amateur and Professional, by W. I. Lincoln Adams, has been cataloged with the Book Collection at the Oregon Historical Society Research Library.
A survey of negatives taken by Walter Boychuk is available at the Oregon Historical Society Research Library, in the Boychuk collection file.
Additional images by Walter Boychuk can be found in the Morris Whitehouse photographs collection, Org. Lot 321, Oregon Historical Society Research Library.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Golden Gate International Exposition (1939-1940: San Francisco, Calif.)--Photographs; Historic American Buildings Survey--Photographs.
Bonneville Dam (Or. and Wash.)--Photographs; Columbia River Gorge (Or. and Wash.)--Photographs; Hood, Mount (Or.)--Photographs; Portland (Or.)--Photographs
Architectural photography; Ships--Oregon--Photographs
Oregon; Washington; Architecture; Ships and shipping
Photographic prints; Photomechanical prints
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Walter and Anna Boychuk biographical materials, 1930-1959; Group 1
  The group includes a folder of background material on the Boychuks and their studio collected in the course of processing the collection. It also includes photographs of Walter and Anna Boychuk and personal greeting cards they created using his photographs.
  - Background, undated (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Anna Boychuk, circa 1930 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Walter Boychuk, 1940 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Greeting cards, 1955, 1956, 1957, 1959 (Box-folder 1/4)
- Prints from original negatives, 1918-1961; Group 2
  The prints made at the Oregon Historical Society from Walter Boychuk’s original negatives represent the full range of his photographic work: architectural, portrait, landscape, and commercial. The Oregon Historical Society made prints from Boychuk’s original negatives circa 1970, and these were placed in the Photograph Subject Files in the Research Library. Around 1998, the Meyer Memorial Trust funded a negative survey and preservation printing of the collection. Prints from both of these projects are included in Group 1.
  - Oregon locations (except Portland), 1912-1961; Series A
    - Cities and towns, 1930-1951; Subseries 1
      - Astoria - Chinook Packing Company receiving station, Tongue Point, circa 1930 (Box-folder 1/5)
      - Aurora - Keil residence, Aurora Colony, circa 1945 (Box-folder 1/6)
      - Bonneville, 1939 (Box-folder 1/7)
      - Champoeg State Park, circa 1935 (Box-folder 1/8)
      - Florence - Bridge over Siuslaw River, 1938 (Box-folder 1/9)
      - Lake Oswego, circa 1935 (Box-folder 1/10)
        Includes images of fireworks display at Kline’s, Marylhurst University, and a smelter stack, among other images
      - Newport - Docks, circa 1935 (Box-folder 1/11)
      - Oregon City - Catholic Church window, circa 1935 (Box-folder 1/12)
      - Oregon City - Willamette Falls, circa 1935 (Box-folder 1/13)
      - Salem - State Office Building, 1951 (Box-folder 1/14)
      - Salem - State Capital Building, 1951 (Box-folder 1/15)
      - Salem - State Capital Building interior, 1951 (Box-folder 1/16)
      - Salem - State Capital monuments, 1951 (Box-folder 1/17)
        Includes one image of Anna Boychuk
      - Salem - State Library Building, 1951 (Box-folder 1/18)
      - Salem - Willamette University, 1938 (Box-folder 1/19)
      - Silverton - Covered Bridges, circa 1935 (Box-folder 1/20)
      - St. Paul - Cemetery, with monument and grave of Rev. F. N. Blanchet, circa 1935 (Box-folder 1/21)
      - Wheatland - George Gay house, circa 1940 (Box-folder 1/22)
        Includes one image of Walter Boychuk in house
    - Bonneville Dam, 1936-1939; Subseries 2
      - Bonneville Dam - Construction, 1936 (Box-folder 1/23)
        Includes images of Walter Boychuk and Anna Boychuk
      - Bonneville Dam - Construction from Munra Point, 1936 May 28 (Box-folder 1/24)
      - Bonneville Dam - Construction, circa 1936 (Box-folder 1/25)
      - Bonneville Locks, 1938 June (Box-folder 1/26)
        Includes Steamer Charles L. Wheeler, Jr., the first ship through the Locks
      - Bonneville Locks - Dedication, 1938 July 9 (Box-folder 1/27)
      - Bonneville Dam, 1938 (Box-folder 1/28)
      - Bonneville Lake Reservoir, 1938 (Box-folder 1/29)
      - Bonneville Dam, 1939 April 4 (Box-folder 1/30)
      - Bonneville Dame Entrance, circa 1939 (Box-folder 1/31)
    - Columbia River Gorge, 1935-1937; Subseries 3
      - Beacon Rock from Columbia River Highway, circa 1939 (Box-folder 2/1)
        Includes McCord Creek Bridge
      - Columbia River, circa 1939 (Box-folder 2/2)
      - Columbia River - Bridge of the Gods, circa 1939 (Box-folder 2/3)
      - Columbia Gorge - Cascade Locks, circa 1936 (Box-folder 2/4)
      - Columbia Gorge - from Chanticleer, circa 1935 (Box-folder 2/5)
        Includes monument at Chanticleer
      - Columbia Gorge - from Crown Point, circa 1935 (Box-folder 2/6)
        Includes Vista House
      - Columbia Gorge - Celilo Falls, 1956 September 9 (Box-folder 2/7)
      - Columbia Gorge - Celilo Falls, 1957 March 9 (Box-folder 2/8)
        Some negatives labeled by Boychuk as, "The day before it was covered."
      - Columbia Gorge - Celilo Falls fishing, circa 1935 (Box-folder 2/9)
      - Columbia Gorge - Celilo Falls fishing, circa 1956-1957 (Box-folder 2/10)
      - Columbia Gorge - Petroglyphs, circa 1935 (Box-folder 2/11)
      - Columbia Gorge - Celilo Falls Tramway, circa 1956-1957 (Box-folder 2/12)
      - Columbia Gorge - Celilo Canal, circa 1936 (Box-folder 2/13)
      - Columbia Gorge - Fishwheel, circa 1935 (Box-folder 2/14)
      - Columbia Gorge - Memaloose Island, 1936 (Box-folder 2/15)
        Anna Boychuk in photograph.
      - Columbia Gorge - San Dunes, circa 1950 (Box-folder 2/16)
      - Columbia Gorge - views, circa 1925 (Box-folder 2/17)
      - Columbia Gorge - views, circa 1943, 1950 (Box-folder 2/18)
      - Columbia Gorge - views, 1936 May 28 (Box-folder 2/19)
        Anna and Walter Boychuk appear in some of the images.
      - Columbia Gorge - Horsetail Falls, circa 1940 (Box-folder 2/20)
      - Columbia Gorge - Maidenhair Falls, circa 1935 (Box-folder 2/21)
      - Columbia Gorge - Multnomah Falls, circa 1935, circa 1940 (Box-folder 2/22)
      - Columbia Gorge - Starvation Creek Falls, circa 1940 (Box-folder 2/23)
      - Columbia Gorge - Wahkeena Falls, circa 1940 (Box-folder 2/24)
      - Columbia Gorge - Wygant Park, circa 1940 (Box-folder 2/25)
      - Columbia River Highway, circa 1935, circa 1940 (Box-folder 2/26)
      - Columbia River Highway - Shepherd's Dell and McCord Creek Bridges, circa 1940 (Box-folder 2/27)
      - Columbia River Highway - Tunnels, 1934, circa 1940 (Box-folder 2/28)
        Includes images of Bonneville Tunnel, Mitchell Point Tunnel, and Oneonta Tunnel.
    - Coast scenery and lighthouses, 1934-1940; Subseries 4
      - Coast - Boiler Bay, circa 1938 (Box-folder 2/29)
      - Coast - Old cannon at Cannon Beach, circa 1938 (Box-folder 2/30)
      - Coast - Cape Kiwanda, circa 1934 (Box-folder 2/31)
      - Coast - Cape Kiwanda, circa 1936 (Box-folder 2/32)
      - Coast - Cape Perpetua lookout, 1936 September 13 (Box-folder 2/33)
      - Coast - Cape San Sebastian, circa 1938 (Box-folder 2/34)
      - Coast - Depot Bay, circa 1938 (Box-folder 2/35)
      - Coast - Ecola Park, circa 1936 (Box-folder 2/36)
      - Coast - Hecata Head, circa 1936 (Box-folder 2/37)
        Anna Boychuk appears in some of the images.
      - Coast - Lighthouses - Cape Disappointment, circa 1938 (Box-folder 3/1)
      - Coast - Lighthouses - Cape Foulweather, circa 1936 (Box-folder 3/2)
      - Coast - Lighthouses - Hecata Head, circa 1936 (Box-folder 3/3)
      - Coast - Lighthouses - North Head, circa 1938 (Box-folder 3/4)
      - Coast - Lighthouses - Umpqua, circa 1936 (Box-folder 3/5)
      - Coast - Newport Bridge, circa 1936-1940 (Box-folder 3/6)
      - Coast - Oceanside Beach, circa 1940 (Box-folder 3/7)
      - Coast View from Otter Rock, circa 1938 (Box-folder 3/8)
      - Coast - San Dunes, circa 1935 (Box-folder 3/9)
      - Coast - Scenes, circa 1938 (Box-folder 3/10)
      - Coast - Sea Lion Cave, circa 1938 (Box-folder 3/11)
        Includes Anna Boychuk in some of the images.
      - Coast - Waldport Bridge, 1936 March 13 (Box-folder 3/12)
      - Coast - Waldport Crab Fishing, circa 1936 (Box-folder 3/13)
      - Coast - Yachts, 1936 September 13 (Box-folder 3/14)
      - Coast - Yaquina Bay, circa 1936 (Box-folder 3/15)
    - Mount Hood, 1923-1950; Subseries 5
      - Mount Hood, circa 1950 (Box-folder 3/16)
        Various scenes depicting bear grass and rhododendrons with Mount Hood in the background. Some images include Anna Boychuk.
      - Mount Hood, circa 1925, 1935, 1945 (Box-folder 3/17)
      - Mount Hood from Bull Run Reserve, circa 1935 (Box-folder 3/18)
      - Mount Hood - Cloud Cap Inn vicinity, 1934 (Box-folder 3/19)
      - Mount Hood - Eden Park, 1923 (Box-folder 3/20)
        Includes image of a Mazamas outing.
      - Mount Hood - Eliot Glacier, circa 1935 (Box-folder 3/21)
      - Mount Hood - Hood River Valley orchards, circa 1935 (Box-folder 3/22)
      - Mount Hood from Hood River Valley, circa 1935 (Box-folder 3/23)
      - Mount Hood from Lost Lake, 1934 (Box-folder 3/24)
        Walter Boychuk appears in some of the images.
      - Mount Hood - Loop Highway in winter, circa 1935 (Box-folder 3/25)
      - Mount Hood - Loop Highway, 1938 (Box-folder 3/26)
      - Mount Hood - Skiing, circa 1935 (Box-folder 4/1)
        Joe Gianini appears in some of the images.
      - Mount Hood - Skiing, Government Camp, circa 1939 (Box-folder 4/2)
      - Mount Hood - Skiing, Walter White, 1939 February 16 (Box-folder 4/3)
      - Mount Hood - South Side, 1939 February 17 and 1939 March 9 (Box-folder 4/4)
      - Mount Hood - South Side, circa 1939 (Box-folder 4/5)
      - Mount Hood from Timberline Lodge, circa 1939 (Box-folder 4/6)
      - Mount Hood - Timberline Lodge, 1939 February 17 and 1939 March 9 (Box-folder 4/7)
      - Mount Hood - Timberline Lodge, snow scenes, 1939 February 16 (Box-folder 4/8)
      - Mount Hood - Timberline Lodge exterior, 1938 (Box-folder 4/9)
      - Mount Hood - Timberline Lodge interior, 1938 (Box-folder 4/10)
      - Mount Hood - Winter, 1939 (Box-folder 4/11)
      - Mount Jefferson from Mount Hood, circa 1935 (Box-folder 4/12)
      - Rural road - snow scene, circa 1935 (Box-folder 4/13)
    - Eastern Oregon, 1945; Subseries 6
      - Eastern Oregon - Adobe House, Old Ford Ruins, circa 1945 (Box-folder 4/14)
      - Eastern Oregon - Harney County, Alvord Ranch, circa 1945 (Box-folder 4/15)
      - Eastern Oregon - Harney County, Steens Mountains, circa 1945 (Box-folder 4/16)
      - Eastern Oregon - Harney County, typical ranch, circa 1945 (Box-folder 4/17)
      - Eastern Oregon - Harney County, circa 1945 (Box-folder 4/18)
        Includes photos of the Whitehorse Ranch and a sod building.
      - Eastern Oregon - Warm Springs Indian Reservation, circa 1945 (Box-folder 4/19)
    - Lakes, 1918-1935; Subseries 7
      - Lakes - Aneroid Lake, Mazamas outing, 1918 (Box-folder 4/20)
      - Lakes - Breitenbush, circa 1920 (Box-folder 4/21)
        Includes photograph of rest hut.
      - Lakes - Crate Lake, 1921 (Box-folder 4/22)
        Taken during a Mazamas outing.
      - Lakes - Crate Lake, Wizard Island, 1921 (Box-folder 4/23)
      - Lakes - Crescent Lake, Diamond Peak, 1921 (Box-folder 4/24)
      - Lakes - East Moreland with swans, circa 1935 (Box-folder 4/25)
      - Lakes - Ice Lake, 1918 (Box-folder 4/26)
      - Lakes - Legion Lake, circa 1935 (Box-folder 4/27)
      - Lakes - Wallowa Lake, 1918 (Box-folder 4/28)
    - Mountains, 1918-1945; Subseries 8
      - Mountains - Eagle Cap, 1918 (Box-folder 5/1)
      - Mountains - Larch Mountain, circa 1925 (Box-folder 5/2)
      - Mountains - Mount Jefferson, circa 1925 (Box-folder 5/3)
      - Mountains - Mount Scott, 1921 (Box-folder 5/4)
      - Mountains - Mount Thiesen, 1921 (Box-folder 5/5)
      - Mountains - Mount Washington, 1922 (Box-folder 5/6)
      - Mountains - Three Sisters, 1922 (Box-folder 5/7)
        Collier Glacier, taken during a Mazamas outing.
      - Mountains - View of the Three Sisters from Bend, circa 1945 (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Rivers, 1918-1945; Subseries 9
      - Rivers - Crooked River, circa 1945 (Box-folder 5/9)
      - Rivers - Wallowa River, 1918 (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Waterfalls, 1925-1935; Subseries 10
      - Waterfalls - Eagle Creek, circa 1925 (Box-folder 5/11)
      - Waterfalls - Silver Creek, circa 1935 (Box-folder 5/12)
      - Waterfalls - Tanner Creek, circa 1925 (Box-folder 5/13)
  - Locations - Portland, 1925-1951; Series B
    - Portland - Airport, Aircraft, 1929, 1933 (Box-folder 5/14)
      Includes image of Fort Tri-Motor and United Airlines Prop Plane.
    - Portland - Airport, circa 1933 (Box-folder 5/15)
    - Portland - Bridges - Broadway, circa 1935 (Box-folder 5/16)
    - Portland - Bridges - Burnside, circa 1935 (Box-folder 5/17)
    - Portland - Bridges - Ross Island, circa 1935 (Box-folder 5/18)
    - Portland - Bridges - St. John's, circa 1936 (Box-folder 5/19)
    - Portland - Bridges - Steel, circa 1935 (Box-folder 5/20)
    - Portland - Buildings - Benson Polytechnic, circa 1935 (Box-folder 5/21)
    - Portland - Buildings - Pacific Telephone, 1951 April 19 (Box-folder 5/22)
    - Portland - Buildings - Equitable Building, 1949 November 25 (Box-folder 5/23)
      Designed by Pietro Belluschi.
    - Portland - Buildings - Federal Building, 1951 April 19 (Box-folder 5/24)
    - Portland - Buildings - First Congregational Church, circa 1935 (Box-folder 5/25)
    - Portland - Buildings - First National Bank, circa 1935 (Box-folder 5/26)
    - Portland - Buildings - Franklin High School, circa 1935 (Box-folder 5/27)
    - Portland - Buildings - Fruit and Flower Mission, circa 1935 (Box-folder 5/28)
    - Portland - Buildings - Jantzen Knitting Mills, circa 1935 (Box-folder 5/29)
    - Portland - Buildings - Masonic Temple, circa 1935 (Box-folder 5/30)
      Designed by Sutton Whitney.
    - Portland - Buildings - Meier and Frank, circa 1925 (Box-folder 5/31)
    - Portland - Buildings - Multnomah County Courthouse, 1925 (Box-folder 5/32)
    - Portland - Buildings - Multnomah County Library, circa 1935 (Box-folder 5/33)
    - Portland - Buildings - Neighbors of Woodcraft, circa 1935 (Box-folder 5/34)
    - Portland - Buildings - Old Forestry Building, circa 1935 (Box-folder 5/35)
    - Portland - Buildings - Old Post Office, circa 1925 (Box-folder 5/36)
    - Portland - Buildings - Portland Art Museum, circa 1936 (Box-folder 5/37)
    - Portland - Buildings - Portland Art Museum, entrance, circa 1936 (Box-folder 5/38)
    - Portland - Buildings - Providence Hospital Smokestack, circa 1935 (Box-folder 5/39)
    - Portland - Buildings - Catholic Cathedral, circa 1935 (Box-folder 5/40)
    - Portland - Buildings - Temple Beth Israel, circa 1935 (Box-folder 5/41)
      Herman Brookman, contributing architect.
    - Portland - Buildings - University Club, circa 1935 (Box-folder 5/42)
      Morris H. Whitehouse, architect.
    - Portland - Buildings - Waverly Baby Home, circa 1931-1931 (Box-folder 5/43)
      Taken for "Joe Portland" promotion.
    - Portland - Firefighting, 1922 August 1 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Portland - Shemanski, circa 1930 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Portland - Skidmore, circa 1935 (Box-folder 6/3-4)
    - Portland - Skidmore, circa 1930 (Box-folder 6/5)
      First Portland Garen Club Flower Show
    - Portland - Fountains - Skidmore in winter, 1935 (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Portland - Harbor - Western Transportation Company, circa 1940 (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Portland - Harbor - Kerr Gifford Elevator, circa 1940 (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Portland - Harbor - Lightshow, circa 1940 (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Portland - Jantzen Beach, circa 1935 (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Portland - KOIN Tower, circa 1935 (Box-folder 6/11)
    - Portland - Marquam Hill, Portland Medical Center, circa 1935 (Box-folder 6/12)
    - Portland - Monuments - Abraham Lincoln, circa 1935 (Box-folder 6/13)
    - Portland - Monuments - Lownsdale Square, circa 1935 (Box-folder 6/14)
    - Portland - Monuments - Theodore Roosevelt, circa 1935 (Box-folder 6/15)
    - Portland - Monuments - Harvey Scott, circa 1935 (Box-folder 6/16)
    - Portland - Monuments - George Washington, circa 1935 (Box-folder 6/17)
    - Portland - Parks - Rocky Butte, circa 1935 (Box-folder 6/18)
    - Portland - Parks - Washington Park, circa 1935 (Box-folder 6/19)
      Includes images of the Rose Garden, "Coming of the White Man" sculpture by Hermon A. MacNeil, and other photographs.
    - Portland - Residences - Jacob Kramm, circa 1930 (Box-folder 6/20)
      Old weeping willow tree.
    - Portland - Residences - Lloyd Frank, circa 1930 (Box-folder 6/21)
      Now Lewis and Clark College.
    - Portland - Residences - A. Lewis Mills, circa 1935 (Box-folder 6/22)
    - Portland - Rose Festival Parade, circa 1935 (Box-folder 6/23)
    - Portland - Rose Festival Parade, circa 1940 (Box-folder 6/24)
    - Portland - Streets - Front Street, circa 1935 (Box-folder 6/25)
    - Portland - Streets - SW Fifth and Morrison, circa 1935 (Box-folder 6/26)
    - Portland - Views - South Portland, circa 1925 (Box-folder 6/27)
    - Portland - Views with Mount Hood, circa 1935 (Box-folder 6/28)
    - Portland - Willamette Rover, circa 1935 (Box-folder 6/29)
    - Portland - Willamette River with Macon Dirigible, 1934 (Box-folder 6/30)